Justin O. Young

5151 West Markwood Ct. West Valley City, UT 84120 (801) 541-9922

jyoung7223@yahoo.com

Candidate is looking to leverage & expand his business and technology skills, in a contract/consulting/free-lance software development/engineering role creating modern day software solutions.

Summary of Qualifications

Solid candidate with excellent problem-solving skills and a great ability to quickly grasp new skills. Candidate has demonstrated an ability to communicate difficult and complex processes in a way that can be understood by members of the technical team and business. Candidate has demonstrated an ability to understand the details of an application/process as well as how it fits into the bigger scheme of things. This has proven to be a valuable asset when designing larger projects that impact multiple areas.

Candidate has been in technology sector for roughly 15 years. Candidate has roughly 12 years, hands-on, developing Java web applications; using Eclipse with Servlets, JSPs, SQL, and the MVC framework and roughly 7 years experience designing and building enterprise-level applications; using Java, REST & SOAP services, JSP, Servlets, HTML, CSS, SQL and JavaScript.

Candidate has proven his ability to fit into multiple roles and has successfully filled the role of Product Owner, Scrum Master, Developer and Architect over the last 7 years in an Agile Scrum environment.

Technical Skills

Development Strategies: Agile (Rally, Jira), Waterfall

Technologies/Tools:

VS Code, Eclipse, Java, REST, SOAP, JavaScript, NodeJS, Servlets, JSP, CSS, HTML, Maven, SpringAOP, Hibernate, BIRT, JavaPOS, SQL, iSQL, XML, UML, Xcode, iOS, Swift, Objective-C, Ingres 4GL, C++, JBoss, Tomcat, WordPress, Citrix XenApp, BIM 360, MS Project Professional, MS SharePoint, MS Office

Computer Systems: Windows, Red Hat Linux, VMWare

Databases: Oracle, MS SQL, Ingres, MySQL

Professional Experience

Management Services

Sep 2020 – Present

VP Technology (Sep 2020 – Present)

Tools Used: VS Code, Java, JavaScript, NodeJS, REST, MS SQL, HTML, XML, UML, BIM, Forge APIs, Revit, Linux, Windows

- Evaluate and improve supporting software solutions.
- Connect and automate business process used during the project management and construction process.
- Develop customize solutions for business operation needs.

Global Access

May 2017 – Aug 2020

Software Engineer (May 2017 – Aug 2020)

Tools Used: Eclipse, Java, SOAP, REST, MS SQL, HTML, Servlets, JSP, JavaScript, XML, UML, Linux, Windows

- Developed customized web-based solutions to manage multiple clients international logistics needs.
- Developed SOAP and REST API integration solutions with international logistics partners.

Infosys Limited (at American Express)

December 2011 - May 2017

Software Development Lead (December 2015 – May 2017)

Tools Used: Agile (Rally, Jira), Eclipse, Java, REST, Oracle SQL, HTML, XML, UML, MS Project Pro, MS Sharepoint, Citrix XenApp, Windows

- Engineered enterprise-level technical solutions and integrations across multiple teams, using both Waterfall and Agile development methods for American Express' Personal Savings portfolio (client of Infosys).
- Engineered Java-based applications that used REST web services to establish a 2-way authentication between Personal Savings & Credit Card products, using OAuth and SAML authentication, utilizing cookies and Oracle databases.

Infosys Limited (at American Express) (continued)

<u>Technical Analyst (December 2011 – December 2015)</u>

Tools Used: Agile (Rally), Eclipse, Java, REST, Maven, Servlets, JSP, Oracle, MS SQL, SQL, iSQL, HTML, XML, JavaScript, Xcode, iOS, Objective C, JBoss, Tomcat, UML, MS Project Pro, MS Sharepoint, MS Office, Citrix XenApp, Windows, Red Hat Linux

- Spearheaded the migration of some of the first teams to transition from Waterfall development to Agile Scrum development using MS Excel/Word then Rally & Jira, while filling scrum-based roles of Developer, Scrum Master & Product Owner for different projects.
- Supported Direct Deposit application by engineering and developing Java-based solutions, utilizing Eclipse with Maven and Spring AOP as the core, and Servlets and

REST services with JavaScript, HTML and JSPs for interfacing/front-end channels and supported by Oracle and IBM DB2 databases.

Developed mobile iOS applications using Xcode and Objective-C utilizing JSON API integrations.

American Digital,

January 2005 – December 2011

Project Development Lead (January 2008 – December 2011)

Tools Used: Waterfall, Eclipse, Java, Servlets, JSP, Hibernate, BIRT, JavaPOS, Ingres 4GL, MySQL, SQL, HTML, XML, JavaScript, Tomcat, Wordpress, UML, MS Office, VMWare, Windows, Red Hat Linux

• Lead engineer & developer for an online charge account service, for retail customers' loyalty cards that used Java Servlets with Hibernate, JSPs, JavaScript and Hibernate, and other technologies.

American Digital (continued)

<u>Lead Programmer (January 2005 – January 2008)</u>

Education and Training

Certification in Full Stack Flex Programming - Mar 2021

University of Utah

• Maintaining up-to-date knowledge on full-stack development technologies and methodologies, through night & weekend classes.

Master of Business Administration – Aug 2016

University of Utah – GPA 3.7/4.0

- Demonstrated good work ethic by working full-time; while attending night classes to get master's degree.
- Gained a good understanding of the business side of operations, which greatly compliments his ability to engineer solutions that better fit the business needs.

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science – May 2007

University of Utah – GPA 3.3/4.0

- Gained a solid background in software development, engineering and technology.
- Worked with a team of 2-3 others to develop a "Scorched Earth" game application server and integrated with more related teams than any other team in our class.

Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering – May 2007 University of Utah – GPA 3.3/4.0

- Gained a good understanding of microprocessors, electronics, circuitry.
- Worked with 1 other teammate to design, engineer and build an electric circuit that would automatically drain a bathtub when it detected inactivity, to help reduce the likelihood of accidental toddler drownings.